<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Interpreting compilers</title><link>https://singh-yashwant.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Interpreting compilers</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 01:20:52 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://singh-yashwant.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Loop Optimizations in compilers[Part 1]</title><link>https://singh-yashwant.github.io/posts/loop-optimizations/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 01:20:52 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://singh-yashwant.github.io/posts/loop-optimizations/</guid><description>Introduction Loops are &amp;ldquo;the&amp;rdquo; most compute intensive part of any software program making loop optimizations some of the most rewarding optimizations for a compiler. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll try to go over some of these optimizations which are covered by LLVM(I&amp;rsquo;m sure you&amp;rsquo;ll find them in other compilers too). This is not an extensive list you can always find more.
Loop Invariant Code Motion (Code hoisting) It&amp;rsquo;s a known coding practice to always keep definitions and constant code outside the loop.</description></item><item><title>Using git worktrees to manage large codebases</title><link>https://singh-yashwant.github.io/posts/git-worktrees/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:01:46 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://singh-yashwant.github.io/posts/git-worktrees/</guid><description>As the first blog in the series let&amp;rsquo;s keep it short and informative.
Introduction If you work on a large scale project like compilers you will always come across the need to have multiple versions as a part of your development arsenal. One might be the latest one(in sync with upstream), one might be for a brand new feature you are working on and the other might be some crash issue that you are investigating.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://singh-yashwant.github.io/about/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://singh-yashwant.github.io/about/about/</guid><description>Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m a compiler engineer currenlty working at Machine Learning and Software Engineering(MLSE) @AMD. I try to write stuff related to compilers and software development</description></item></channel></rss>